- [Instructor] Okay, so let's work
on the listing of our players component.
So the first thing I'm going to do is go inside of my terminal
and stop the server.
So I'm going to delete this front end here,
and I'm going to, basically, start it over
and make sure I'm on the front end
and I'm going to install Axios.
So Axios Is going to be used to query the back end server,
npm install Axios, and you want to make sure
you're on the front end, FYI, 'cause if you install this
at the root directory, you're going to install it
in the wrong directory.
You're going to have, basically a package.JSON.
Here, you shouldn't have that.
So make sure you're in the front end and install Axios.
When this is done, you can start the server again
so we can see what we're doing, and then minimize this again
just to get it out of the way.
All right, so the first thing,
we're going to start adding some code
and the app will get back to the player list after.
So what I'm going to do first is make sure that
I have the state initiated in my class component.
So just above the render,
I'm going to add a constructor with props
and initiate my state right here.
So let's go ahead and do this,
props and this.state = players,
which will be an array, and then currentPlayer,
which we'll need when we select a player.
We'll need a current player, which will be an object,
and this is all we need.
Now, what we need, first, again, above the render,
we need to have this function
that will, basically, use Axios,
and then we should actually import it
while we're thinking about it from 'axios',
so when the component did mount,
we need to get the list of players from the backend.
So what we're going to do is, first of all,
I'm going to create a variable with the URL of our server.
So this could be anything.
So if you're building your server in the cloud,
you want to make sure you have the right URL here,
but since we're doing this locally,
this is going to be my URL and players.
So this is where we're going to use that URL
to load the players.
So we're going to call into our API or endpoint
that we've created with the backend
and use Axios to get the data from our backend.
So get from the URL, and then with the response
from the server, which, as you remember,
will return an array, do this.
So we're going to set the state.
So we're going to update the state with the players,
So the players, that, now, is an empty array.
In our constructor, we're going to pass
the data from the response.
So whatever is the data or, basically, the array
that we receive from the backend server,
go ahead and update our state right here.
So now, we're going to have an array
with multiple players, right?
So now, again, we need to catch if there's an error
and catch the error like so.
So if there's an error, pass it to the console log,
and let me know what's happening here.
All right, so now we need to use this, right?
So we need to pass it to something,
and then we're going to update that component accordingly.
So in this case, what we want to do
is pass a prop of players from the state,
this.state.players.
So now, in this player list, we're going to have access
to this prop that we've passed from the state.
So let's save this, and now, we're going to go
inside of our player.
Your application, it actually should run properly
'cause you're passing it properly here,
and you're not using it on the player list
or we're going to update the player list
accordingly as well,
and what we're going to do, instead of doing player list,
we're going to change this
to leverage what we got from our props,
and you want to make sure you pass props here
'cause, otherwise, you're not going to have access to this.
All right, now, what we're going to do is use a ul,
and we're going to pass a few things from materialize,
which is a collection with-header,
and we're going to have an li class name collection-header,
and this is going to be Players,
and this is where we're going to pass what we need.
Okay, so here, we need to leverage the props,
which is players.
So we have the props, which is players,
and we're going to map it.
So for each item, you're going to do this.
We're going to have an href, so we'll use this,
className="collection-item",
and we're going to need to pass a unique key.
So the unique key will be the item.id,
and then we're going to need to close this, actually,
so close this href, which we haven't done like so,
and inside of that link,
we're going to have the item.firstName.
Remember, our database has a first name,
space item.lastName,
and the other thing that we're going to do
is pass a function, eventually.
So what I'm going to do is, just for now,
I'm going to create the function
in the app here very quickly.
So below the component that mount,
I'm going to create a updateCurrentPlayer with an item,
and I'm going to set the state
with the currentPlayer with the item,
and I'm going to pass this function as well here.
So let's do a return on here
like this.
So you want to be in the player list component
'cause we're going to pass this function to the component,
updateCurrentPlayer=, okay.
So this is all going to make sense later.
I'm going to explain it in the future,
but this function will allow us to update
who is the current player that will be displayed
in the player single.
So for now, I'm just passing the function here,
and I'm going to use it here as well.
So there's a lot that's happening in this particular video,
but all of it is going to make sense
as we finish our other components,
and, actually, here on the link, you want to make sure
you're inside of the A tag here.
So make sure you're before here,
and you can return this if you want to have more space.
We're going to add an onClick
and pass the props.updateCurrentPlayer,
and we're going to bind this function,
and we're going to pass this.item as the current player.
Okay, perfect.
So that completes this particular part.
As you can see, everything is working properly.
If you want to go and check the application,
right now, it isn't working properly
'cause there are things missing in the application,
which is normal,
and if there's anything else that's not working,
and you can see that everything,
so far, we've done, is working.
All of these, don't worry about it, it's okay,
and what we're going to do is as we complete
the other parts of the application,
all of this is going to work.
Let's move on.